MARK AMANNS

(513)753-3332 <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Email</u>

I have worked with computers, database languages and servers for many years, including as a programmer/analyst on a team supporting an insurance company's systems. I have always been a problem solver with a detective mindset, having a zeal for seeking out solutions for both software bugs and detailed project designs. At Tech Elevator I am updating and expanding my legacy coding skills to include today's technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- .Net Language Fundamentals: C# variables, data types, loops, conditional statements, exception handling, collections framework, I/O
- **Object Oriented Programming:** classes and objects, interfaces, inheritance
- Web Application Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, JSON, XML
- **Database Programming:** table design and creation, SQL queries, techniques and priorities during conversion
- Windows and SQL Server experience: monitoring COM objects and server status
- **Legacy database programming experience:** many years with Visual FoxPro versions 6-9, FoxPro for DOS/Windows, dBase for DOS

EDUCATION

Tech Elevator - Cincinnati, OH

September 2018 - Current

14 week .Net coding boot camp and in-person educational platform focused on developing dynamic workstation and web-based software systems using the .Net programming language and platform.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Transamerica Retirement Solutions – West Chester, OH

May 2001 – February 2017

Senior Systems Analyst – Programming languages: Visual FoxPro versions 6-9, dBase 5 for DOS, JavaScript, XML, Java, Eclipse.

Charles H. Mack & Associates (acquired 2014 by AssureCare) – Cincinnati, OH May 1998 – February 2001 Programmer/Analyst – Programming languages: FoxPro for DOS/Windows, Visual FoxPro version 6, Visual Basic 6.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

- Continuum of Care (senior services) system support and enhancement: Developed, modified and debugged modules for a software tracking and logging system used by Cincinnati Council on Aging and other counties in Ohio and other states.
- Y2K compliance testing and modifications: Handled all fixes in advance for CoC Y2K issues.
- **System Conversions:** Twice wrote conversion code to convert and push data (ETL) from systems using free tables to SQL server databases.
- **Record Keeping System support and enhancement:** Developed, modified, enhanced and debugged modules in OOP applications which processed, tracked and reported both sponsor

aggregate and end user transactions with details based on retirement money sources, transaction types, fund selections, dates, gain/loss, interest earned/paid, balances, loans taken from multiple money sources, loan payments, etc. Wrote dozens of reports for staff workstation use as well as website access.

- **Q/A and bug fixes:** handling client reports of issues, coding bug research and solutions.
- **Application Development:** Developed solutions using required database applications along with Java, XML, JavaScript, VBScript, SQL databases and COM apps on servers on an as needed basis.